Matthew Lowe

Software/Web Developer

(+1) 416 660 7973

<u>Matthewjlowe11@gmail.com</u>

<u>https://github.com/7daytheory</u>

<u>https://7daytheory.github.io/portfolio-react</u>

Overview

I have 10 years of experience working in the industry working as a frontend and back-end developer, as well as database management and hosting. I have worked extensively in Javascript, PHP, MySQL and NoSQL databases, using and creating APIs, and many frameworks including React, Angular, JQuery, CakePHP, and Laravel. including frameworks like React and Angular. I have brought multiple projects from start to deployement stages with version control integrated. I am confident that I can be an asset to any company that requires a developer but I also try to always be learning more.

EXPERIENCE

ShipEarly

2023 – 2024 (9-month contract)

Full Stack Developer

- Joined a small startup on a contract to help them grow
- Worked on their back end using Cake 2 PHP to develop a sales system that was integrated with salesforce
- Worked with Git, did code reviews and integrated it with Trello
- They had no work meetings, and I had talked to them about needing to communicate often and they would not – so found it was not the right place for me after my contract was up

Quillsoft

2017 - 2023

Developer

- Created and oversaw growth of the CRM system to ensure our tech team had all the data required to properly assist all our users
- Built a PWA of our main desktop application which has become one of our main apps sold to schools
- Developed a license management system that is currently integrated into all our applications and programs
- Implemented the most up to date encryption methods to keep data secure

Strategic

2012 - 2017

Developer

- **Transitions Inc**
- Created and license management system and integrated it into the web applications and desktop programs
- Responsible for creating encryption for the user's data security
- Developed a customized CMS system from scratch to allow for quick changes of content on the website
- Wireframed, designed, and coded all the company's websites

NeXsys

2011

BPMS Administrator(Summer)

- Created and license management system and integrated it into the web applications and desktop programs
- Responsible for creating encryption for the user's data security
- Developed a customized CMS system from scratch to allow for quick changes of content on the website
- Wireframed, designed, and coded all the company's websites

EDUCATION

Fanshawe College

2008-2011

Interactive Media & Production

- The program at Fanshawe had 2 years of general graphic design, video, game design, and mainly web/app development classes
- The 3rd year you picked a specialty; I chose web/app development but still have knowledge in the other areas which has been useful
- I did a project with Strategic Transitions Inc my final year in the program and was the only person hired; I was employed before I finished the program
- I also finished a year in a graphic design program but found I wanted to work more with web and coding that just design and switched to this course

SKILLS

Outgoing / Self-Driven / Accountable / Independant / Proactively identify new tasks / Collaborating with colleagues / Always learning

References Available Upon Request